{"question": "What does likeness bring to society?", "answer": "Likeness brings recognition whereas unlike mindness helps in generating new ideas."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "1 Man & Society The term society is derived from the Latin word \u201csocius\u201d which means companion, associate, comrade or business partner."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Nepal and India share the society of Hindus."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Society refers to the group of people, but to the complex pattern of the norms of interaction that arise among them."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Man needs society for his living, working and enjoying life."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "For the health of society it is essential that there must be a like-minded and unlike minded people."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Cuber has defined society, as a group of individuals who have lived together long enough to become organized and consider themselves distinct from others."}{"question": "According to MacIver, what was the first form of society?", "answer": "According to MacIver, family was the first form of the society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Man forms the society and develops standard and norms."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "No infant could reach maturity without the care of other people."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Chapter 1: History of engineering practices 1."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Although nations may contain several societies, not all these societies are necessarily equal in power or benefit equally from social, political, and economic arrangements."}{"question": "What does the word society mean?", "answer": "It indicates that man lives in company of other people."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Definition of society Society has been defined differently by different scholars."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "A society is an organization of people who share a common territory, govern themselves, and cooperate to secure the survival of the group."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "The presence of many societies within a single nation can become a source of serious conflicts and sometimes war."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "According to Giddings \u2013 \u201cSociety is the union itself, the sum of formal relations which associating individuals are bound together\u201d J."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Society means collection of individuals united by certain relations or modes of behavior which make them off from others who do not enter into these relations."}{"question": "What does Aristotle say about man?", "answer": "Aristotle said \u201cMan is a social animal\u201d."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "The world system is a network of many nations and societies."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Man is a social animal."}{"question": "What is the backbone of society?", "answer": "Invisible likeness and active cooperation is the backbone of society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "F."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "Iraq and Iran share the society of Kurds."}{"question": "What was the role of the Kurds in Iraq?", "answer": "For example, The Kurds in Iraq were oppressed by a more powerful prevailing society under late Suddam Hussein."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "And although blacks in South Africa are now in political majority, for many years they were exploited and oppressed economically, socially, and politically by the dominant white society in that country."}{"question": "What is the meaning of society?", "answer": "It is difficult to live without society."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Not all societies are nations; there may be several societies within a single nation."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Society (definition summary): \u2022 Group of People(collection of individuals) \u2022 Sharing common territory/boundary of a country \u2022 Sharing common rules/regulation (government) \u2022 Sharing common culture/belief/value \u2022 Considered as a stable institution \u2022 A formal association of people with similar interests \u2022 The state of being with someone Elements of Society: \u2022 Plurality (male/female/young/old) \u2022 Differences (opinion/gender/interest) \u2022 Dynamic(changeability/inherit quality) \u2022 Interdependence (Like mother & baby) \u2022 Cooperation(like in family,friendship) \u2022 Likeness(Blood/nationality) \u2022 Mutual understanding/interaction,/awareness \u2022 Social control/Stability \u2022 Culture(traditions, activities, values) Social structure/Social needs To survive, every society must successfully address the same fundamental social needs."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Sociology is the scientific, or academic, study of society and human behavior."}{"question": "What are the main threats to society?", "answer": "Internal threats include crime like robbery, murder, rape and health epidemics like AIDS, measles, polio, and the flu."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "All societies must organize the activities of the members to obtain the basic goods and services necessary for survival (such as food, clothing, shelter, fuel, potable water)."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "It is the web of social relationship\u201d."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "New members must also be taught the skills they will need to participate as productive member of the society."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Whenever societies gain new members, they must transmit knowledge of the rights, obligations, responsibilities, and expectations of appropriate behavior to the new members."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Most appropriate definition of the term society given by Maclver is that \u201cThe society is the system of usages and procedures, of authority and mutual aid, of many groupings and divisions of controls of human behaviors and liberties."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of society?", "answer": "Talcott Parsons identified six basic fundamental social needs as follows: 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "2."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "Societies must protect their members from both external and internal threats."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "Society gives content, direction, and meaning to our lives, and we in turn, in countless ways, reshape the society that we live to the next generation."}{"question": "What are the main threats to society?", "answer": "External threats includes invasion by other societies and destructive natural disasters like hurricanes, tornadoes and earthquakes."}{"question": "What is the definition of society?", "answer": "All societies must replace members lost by death or emigration."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "6."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "2."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the religion?", "answer": "The Religion: Religion manifestly motivates members to comply with their responsibilities and obligations by assigning meaning and purpose to such activities."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of societies?", "answer": "Finally, societies must develop mechanisms for solving conflicts."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "1."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of society?", "answer": "They also discipline and motivate members of society to perform their role in the production, distribution, and consumption of goods and services."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions in the United States?", "answer": "They are: the family, religion, economy, education, and the state."}{"question": "What is the function of the family?", "answer": "The Family: The family is the institution whose manifest function is to contribute new members to society."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "Social Structure / Social needs : Summary For the survival, every society must address some fundamental needs."}{"question": "What are the basic social institutions?", "answer": "Development ( of mechanism for solving conflicts) Social Institutions Five basic institutions can be found in all known societies."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "5."}{"question": "Why did President Bush go to war?", "answer": "Indeed, President Bush argued that it was necessary to go to war \u201cto protect our way of life\u201d, because Iraq\u2019s invasion of Kuwait threatened U."}{"question": "What is the role of the family in a society?", "answer": "Family also teaches the new members what is expected of them, and they try to motivate members to fulfill those expectations."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "S."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "Families may reinforce race, gender, and class inequalities in the way they transmit expectations regarding appropriate behaviors and goals."}{"question": "What is the role of the family in a conflict?", "answer": "Religion attempts to reinforce the family\u2019s transmission of appropriate behaviors and goals to new members of society, and it parallels the family\u2019s role as a mechanism of conflict resolution."}{"question": "What are the basic needs of a society?", "answer": "society from external threats."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "On this regard Talcott Parsons (American sociologist) identified six basic fundamental social needs."}{"question": "What are the basic needs of society?", "answer": "Institutions may even provoke or exacerbate systemic inequalities between groups within society."}{"question": "What are the basic needs of society?", "answer": "All society must motivate both new and continuing members to fulfill their responsibilities and conform to expected behaviors."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the economy in the United States?", "answer": "The Economy: In U."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the economy?", "answer": "access to Mideast oil."}{"question": "What are the basic needs of a society?", "answer": "Each institution is intended to address one or more of the basic needs determining society\u2019s survival."}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "Protection (of members from external & internal threats) \u2022 Replacement(of members lost by death or immigration) \u2022 Transmission (of knowledge to the new members- regarding :rights/obligation/responsibilities/expectation) \u2022 Motivation (to both new & continuing members to fulfill their responsibility & confirm to expected behavior)?"}{"question": "What are the basic social needs of a society?", "answer": "\u2022 Organizing the activities ( to obtain basic goods & services \u2013food/clothing/shelter/fuel/water)?"}{"question": "What was the purpose of the family?", "answer": "For example, when the U."}{"question": "What is the purpose of economic institutions?", "answer": "The purpose of economic institutions is primarily to produce and distribute goods and services throughout society."}{"question": "What are the institutions of the economy?", "answer": "the institutions of the economy includes corporations, organized markets, the banking community, international trade associations, labor unions, and consumer organizations."}{"question": "What was the purpose of the war?", "answer": "went to war against Iraq in early 1991, the state was fulfilling its function of protecting U."}{"question": "Where can one find these people?", "answer": "Even today one can find this handful of isolated people living in the Australian deserts and in the deep interiors of India."}{"question": "What are the basic types of societies?", "answer": "But these societies have been classified into a limited member of basic types depending on the technologies they adopted exploit the natural environment."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions of the tribes?", "answer": "Tribal societies have common territory, a sense of unity, common language, blood relationship, endogamous (customs permitting a man to marry within the tribe), worship common god."}{"question": "What is the role of the state in promoting social change?", "answer": "The state may reinforce other inequalities as well."}{"question": "What was the subsistence strategy of these societies?", "answer": "This was the subsistence strategy of these societies."}{"question": "What is the purpose of education?", "answer": "Education: The manifest function of education is to transmit the skills that all young members of society need to become productive members of the economy as adults."}{"question": "What are the types of societies?", "answer": "Agricultural societies 2."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of the societies?", "answer": "Different societies have used different subsistence strategies while exploiting the food resources."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions of a tribal society?", "answer": "Pastoral societies 5."}{"question": "What are the main functions of educational institutions?", "answer": "Educational institutions can also be powerful mechanisms for social change."}{"question": "What is the only defined institution in these societies?", "answer": "The family is the only defined institution in these societies."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions in the world?", "answer": "Social Institutions summary: Five Basic Institutions can be found in all known societies, which are enumerated below."}{"question": "What is the function of education?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What are the types of societies?", "answer": "Types of societies are as follows: 1."}{"question": "What are the main types of societies?", "answer": "Tribal societies 4."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions of a society?", "answer": "5."}{"question": "What is the trend of socio-cultural evolution?", "answer": "The existence of present day societies has a trend of socio-cultural evolution."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the state?", "answer": "Each tribe knows the norms and standards of behavior and is watched that younger learn the proper way of behaving."}{"question": "What is the definition of a tribal?", "answer": "A tribal is a primitive society which existed in the early period of human history."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the state?", "answer": "Finally, the state aid the economy by developing social welfare programs that distribute goods and services to individuals the economy can not support."}{"question": "What is the role of the state in society?", "answer": "The state also establishes penal and codes to formally define standards of acceptable and unacceptable behaviors, responsibilities and obligations, and it specifies sanctions for violations of these standards."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions of a society?", "answer": "Their needs are simple and easily satisfied spending less time working for their food than the average inhabitants of any other type of society."}{"question": "What are the basic institutions of society?", "answer": "\u2022 Family \u2022 Religion \u2022 Economy \u2022 Education \u2022 State \u2013 Politics, Warfare, Art & Leisure Types of societies Thousands of societies have existed on this planet since time immemorial."}{"question": "What was the subsistence strategy of these societies?", "answer": "Horticultural societies Tribal societies A few thousand years ago, human being relied on hunting and gathering for their survival."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the state?", "answer": "By enhancing the ability of the poor to consume goods and services, state directly support the private producers and the economy."}{"question": "What is the role of the state in society?", "answer": "The State: State protects society\u2019s members from both external and internal threats."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of a society?", "answer": "When skills taught by school include independent, critical, and creative thinking, they produce the potential for challenges to society to alter inequalities and discrimination."}{"question": "What are the types of societies?", "answer": "Industrial societies 3."}{"question": "What is the difference between a purely agricultural society and a pastoral society?", "answer": "Agricultural societies The agricultural wealth of the society was unevenly distributed with a small majority of people enjoying the surplus produce by the working society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the passage?", "answer": "The religions of agricultural societies often include a belief in a \u2018family\u2019 of gods."}{"question": "What was the main purpose of the society?", "answer": "This society produced bulk quantity to feed the majority."}{"question": "What is the main characteristic of industrial society?", "answer": "Division of labor in factories and in management predominates in industrial society."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of horticultural societies?", "answer": "Many horticultural societies are still in existence in Africa, Asia, South America and Australia."}{"question": "What is the need for military set up?", "answer": "These conditions create the need of military set up."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the word?", "answer": "One of these is a high god regarded as more powerful god than other god."}{"question": "What is the basis of industrial society?", "answer": "Industrial societies Application of scientific knowledge to the technology of production is the basis of industrial society."}{"question": "What were the political institutions?", "answer": "Political institutions were more elaborated."}{"question": "What was the role of the monarchy in the development of the society?", "answer": "Power was concentrated in the hands of a single individual and heredity monarchy prevailed."}{"question": "What is the nature of the societies?", "answer": "Agricultural societies tend to be at war constantly."}{"question": "What is the difference between the two?", "answer": "Horticulture became necessarily alternative to pastoral people."}{"question": "What is the difference between a pastoral society and a hunting society?", "answer": "Horticulture provided an assured supply of food and surplus that enabled some individuals wealthy and more powerful than others."}{"question": "What is the difference between agricultural and pastoral societies?", "answer": "Trade is more elaborated in agricultural society."}{"question": "What is the main difference between pastoral societies and other religious societies?", "answer": "They usually believe in a god or gods who take an active interest in human affairs and look after the people who worship them."}{"question": "What was the history of the pastoral societies?", "answer": "Pastoral societies Some ten to twelve thousands years ago a few hunting and gathering tribal started domestication of herds of animals."}{"question": "What is the need for efficient communication and transportation in these large societies?", "answer": "The need for efficient communication and transportation was developed in these large societies."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of industrial societies?", "answer": "New technologies \u2013 such as steam engine, electrical power tend to bring about social change."}{"question": "What is used as a medium of exchange in agricultural societies?", "answer": "Money is used as medium of exchange."}{"question": "What is the main characteristic of industrial society?", "answer": "Growth and development of trade unions is also an important characteristic of industrial society."}{"question": "What is the history of pastoral societies?", "answer": "This strategy of subsistence (existence) gave birth to pastoral societies."}{"question": "What was the first type of society?", "answer": "This society was found practicing a new system of production and distribution."}{"question": "What is the difference between horticultural and pastoral societies?", "answer": "Horticultural societies These societies specialize in the domestication of plants which they cultivate manually with hoes."}{"question": "What religions originated among pastoral people?", "answer": "A few religions such as Judaism (the religion of the Jewish people), Christianity and Islam originated among pastoral people."}{"question": "What is the main difference between industrial and pastoral societies?", "answer": "Industrial revolution gave birth to industrial societies."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the passage?", "answer": "P."}{"question": "What is the main reason for the change in the society?", "answer": "Dynamic and ongoing process \u2022 Progressive transformation of society \u2022 Subject to constant change \u2022 MacIver: Change in the human relationshipM."}{"question": "What was the history of the pastoral societies?", "answer": "\u2022 Pastoral societies (Ten to Twelve thousands years before) -categorized by domestication of herds of animals/ typically found in mountainous region and in areas with insufficient rainfall to support horticultural & agricultural societies/ family & religion are major two institution which was appeared in this society/Slavery is more common in this society \u2022 Horticultural societies(developed between 13000 to 7000 B."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the passage?", "answer": "C."}{"question": "What is the history of the pastoral societies?", "answer": ") \u2013 produce food by gardening (domestication of plants)/ cultivate manually/ this society was occurred due to large declination of animals/ the gardens were usually made by clearing(slash and burn) a forested area and planting the crops/ the people in this society used to move on to make new gardens as the forest reclaimed the garden and the soil lost nutrients (no plow system)/ family,economy religion are the major social institutions exists in this society/ slavery is fairly common \u2022 Agricultural (Agrarian) societies(6000 years ago) \u2013 plow was invented/ maintained the fertility of the soil by turning top soil using plow/ first society to develop city/ permanent settlements /Trade elaborated/money used as medium of exchange/ all the social institutions (family, religion, economy, politics, education, art & leisure,warfare) was developed more elaborately & move towards complexity \u2022 Industrial societies(280 year before)\u2013 characterized by use of machine rather than animals including human / planet\u2019s first industrial society was England / majority of people live in urban areas rather than rural settings / all the social institutions (family, religion, economy, politics, science, education, art & leisure,warfare) was developed more elaborately & move towards complexity / Industrial revolution gave birth of industrial societies/ production & distribution, establishment of trade unions Social Change: \u2022 Change in the society due to alteration in patterns of culture, social structure and social behavior over time?"}{"question": "what is technology?", "answer": "Technology is a systematic knowledge which facilitates in the use of machines and tools."}{"question": "how are technology and social change connected?", "answer": "Technology and social change are intimately connected, particularly in the modern world, where rapid technological and social change tends to go hand in hand."}{"question": "what is the definition of technology?", "answer": "\u2022 Technology \u2013 Use of computer, mobiles/ kitchen gadgets to automobiles \u2022 Geography \u2013 Oceans/deserts/mountain ranges/jungles \u2022 Environment \u2013 Hurricanes/Landslides/Fires/ Earthquake/Greenhouse effect \u2022 Population- Significant decrease or decrease in population size or growth rates may disrupt social life \u2022 Human actions - Ideas/opinion/social conflicts/social movements/invasion 1."}{"question": "what are examples of technologies?", "answer": "These all are the examples of technologies, the practical application of scientific or other knowledge."}{"question": "what is technology?", "answer": "Technology - summary: \u2022 Part of knowledge that deals with the creation and use of technical means and their interrelation with life, society, and the environment, drawing upon such subjects as industrial arts, engineering, applied science, and pure science."}{"question": "What are the examples of technology?", "answer": "Over the generations, simple tools and machines made by human beings such as the knife, the wheel, the plough, the compass, the clocks, the printing press, the steam engines, the nuclear reactors, the computer, the mobile phones, etc have dramatically influenced our social and natural surroundings."}{"question": "what is the difference between technology and human progress?", "answer": "Many people in modern societies seem to implicitly assume that technological development and human progress is much the same thing."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "\u2022 Practical application of systematic knowledgeusing machine and toolsresulting high productivity and higher efficiency for the satisfaction of requirements such as utility, usability & safety Technology Input Output Technical change: \u2022 Modification \u2022 Alteration Achieved from Information, Technique &Tools \u2022 Innovation Technology and social change are intimately connected, particularly in the modern world, where rapid technological and social change tends to go hand in hand."}{"question": "what is the most distinctive of all human characteristics?", "answer": "One of the most distinctive of all human characteristics is that men are tool-using animals."}{"question": "what is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "People have used increasingly sophisticated techniques to act on the social and the natural world for thousands of years and they have done so in many ways that have transformed, and continue to transform, the very conditions of life on this planet."}{"question": "what is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "2 Technology& Society The term technology refers to how input is transferred to output."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "g."}{"question": "What are the major ethical implications of technological development?", "answer": "implicitly assume that technological development and human progress is much the same thing Impact & consequences of technology on society: Technological development(Media Player/Mobile) \u2022 Economics & Technological development ( earlier \u2013 occasional & spontaneous exchange of goods & services) \u2022 Values (Change in expectation & realities/ Mechanistic world view, Efficiency, Social progress) \u2022 Ethics- According to Winston, four major ethical implications of technological development are (a)Challenges traditional ethical norms (b)Creates an aggregation of effects (c) Changes the distribution of justice (d)Provides great power \u2022 Lifestyle \u2013 a) simplifications of life : rise of leisure class/ quick responses to events & trends /global networking/cheaper prices/specialization in jobs b) complications of life :Pollution /Congestion /New forms of danger /New forms of entertainment/increased probability of some diseases & disorders/social separation of singular human interaction \u2022 Institutions and groups: (Rise of very large organizations e."}{"question": "What is the definition of social change?", "answer": "Movement of traditional societies from traditional to industrialization is an example of social change."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the passage?", "answer": "Many simple societies like tribal, pastoral, horticultural, and agricultural societies have grown steadily larger, and some of them have been transformed into the industrial and postindustrial societies of the modern world."}{"question": "What is the definition of social change?", "answer": "In short, social change is simply a means of getting from one form of social stability to another."}{"question": "What is the meaning of 'imbalances'?", "answer": "Imbalances means system has to adjust to new equilibrium."}{"question": "What is the meaning of evolution theory?", "answer": "Evolution theory assumes that social change occurs for betterment."}{"question": "Who laid the basis for functionalism?", "answer": "Emile Durkheim laid the basis for functionalism."}{"question": "What is the meaning of social change?", "answer": "This theory has emphasized social order rather than social change."}{"question": "What is the definition of socio-cultural evolution?", "answer": "\u2022 Mechanical life style \u2022 Formal type of relationships \u2022 Change in existing social customs \u2022 Less family ties between family members Technological change & Religion: \u2022 Analysis of religious doctrines & traditions \u2022 Rigidity in caste system has been relaxed \u2022 Men are free from religious ritual \u2022 Religion has become secondary thing not a primary one Technological change &rural life: \u2022 Migration towards urban areas \u2022 Increase in consciousness of rural people \u2022 Life become comfortable than before \u2022 Change in life pattern Technological change & Urban Life: \u2022 Shortage of land and houses \u2022 Increase in slums \u2022 Problem of transportation \u2022 Increase in crimes \u2022 Expensive life \u2022 Money has become the most important thing \u2022 Lack of security Theories of social change: 1) Socio-cultural evolution theory: Evolutionary process implies that societies would necessarily reach new and higher level of civilization."}{"question": "What is the meaning of social change?", "answer": "Parsons viewed that social change occurs when internal or external strains such as unemployment or war through the system out of balance."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the passage?", "answer": "Summary \u2022 Developed from simple beginning into ever more complex forms (horticulturist /hunters) \u2022 Assumption based on anthropological/historical evidence \u2022 Influence of Charles Darwin\u2019s organic evolution \u2022 Evolutionary process implies that societies would necessarily reach new & high level of civilization 2) Functionalist theory: Talcott Parsons argued that a society consists of interdependent parts each of which helps to maintain the stability of the entire social system which has a tendency to seek equilibrium and balance."}{"question": "What is the definition of socio-cultural evolution?", "answer": "Socio-cultural evolution theory is based on the assumption that societies gradually develop from simple beginnings into ever more complex forms."}{"question": "What is the definition of a social imbalance?", "answer": "This imbalance provokes adjustments that help bring the system back into equilibrium once more built the new equilibrium establishing different social arrangements and cultural components than the previous one."}{"question": "What is the assumption of evolution?", "answer": "This assumption rests on both anthropological and historical evidence."}{"question": "What is the nature of the society?", "answer": "The nature of response determines the fate of society."}{"question": "What is the nature of the civilization?", "answer": "The achievements of the civilization consist of its successful responses to challenges, if it cannot mount an effective response it dies."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of conflict theory?", "answer": "Each society faces challenges at first from environment, internal enemies, external enemies etc."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "By living together for years in a definite part of territory, a sort of relation with people or social likeness is established."}{"question": "What is the definition of conflict theory?", "answer": "Conflict theorists regard conflict as inevitable and normal process."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "This fact of social living, likeness among these in specific area gives birth to community."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "Conflict theory of social change holds that many changes are caused by tensions between competing interests in the society."}{"question": "What is the definition of a conflict theory?", "answer": "Man cannot live in isolation."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "Summary \u2022 Focus on the rise & fall of civilization attempting to discover & account for these pattern of growth & decay \u2022 Assumes that each civilization is like a biological organism & has a similar life cycle/birth/maturity/old age & death \u2022 Each society faces challenges at first from environment/internal enemies/external enemies Community When the members of a group live together and share no particular interest but the basic condition of common life."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "This theory assumes that the existing social conditions always contain the seeds of new social change."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "Summary \u2022 Developed by Karl Marx &later developed by sociologist \u2022 Social change is the result of the conflicts between classes existing in the society \u2022 Different classes of different interest \u2022 Classes are fundamentally on the economy based \u2022 Based on the condition of economic production \u2022 The form of society can be defined as socialist/slave/feudal/capitalist/communist 4) Cyclical theory: This theory assumes that each civilization is like a biological organism and has a similar life-cycle: birth, maturity, old age and death."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "Man is linked in many ways to his fellows in many ways who form a group."}{"question": "What is the definition of a community?", "answer": "Community is a cluster of people living with a narrow territorial radius, who share a common way of life."}{"question": "What is the definition of a social change?", "answer": "Based on the condition of economic production, the form of society is defined as: primitive socialist, slave, feudal, capitalist, socialist and finally communist society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of conflict theory?", "answer": "Summary \u2022 Developed from simple beginning into ever more complex forms (horticulturist /hunters) \u2022 Assumes that society consist of interdependent parts, each of which helps to maintain the stability of the entire social system \u2022 Social change occurs when internal or external strain such as unemployment or war throws the system out of balance 3) Conflict theory: Conflict theory was developed by Karl Marx and has been modified and developed by later sociologists."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "7."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "A community is essentially the group of people sharing the common feeling and basic conditions of a common life."}{"question": "What does it occupy?", "answer": "It occupies a territorial area."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "6."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "It is It has wide scope and is thus of more homogenous group."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "2."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "In village one can still find feeling of community sentiments."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "Group of people residing in a definite locality form a community."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "A community has no legal status."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What are the common objectives of community?", "answer": "Common objectives are loosely Common objectives are closely coordinated."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "9."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "communities."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "5."}{"question": "What is the difference between community and society?", "answer": "heterogeneous character."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "Feeling of community sentiments is another important characteristic of a community."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "Likeness in language and customs is significant elements of community."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "Community is not created and made by an act of will but its emergence is quite natural."}{"question": "What does the word community mean?", "answer": "In cities and towns feeling of sentiments lacks drastically."}{"question": "What is more important in community than population?", "answer": "is that the members should have feeling of oneness as well."}{"question": "What is the legal status of a community?", "answer": "It can neither sue nor to be sued."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "According to Ginsberg, \u201cCommunity is a group of social being living a common life including all the infinite variety and complexity of relations which result from that common life or constitute it\u201d."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "Blaire and Meeca said, \u201cA human community is a functionally related aggregate of people who live in a particular geographic locality at a particular time, share a common culture, are arranged in a social structure, and exhibit an awareness of their uniqueness and separate identity as a group\u201d."}{"question": "What is the difference between community and society?", "answer": "Comparison betweencommunity and society 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "living in far off areas can form a society."}{"question": "What is the scope of community?", "answer": "Its scope is narrow and localized."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "8."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "coordinated."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "Community came after society and in a Society came prior to community and its community there cannot be many scope is wide, as it embraces many communities."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "Every community has some specific and particular name."}{"question": "What is the meaning of community?", "answer": "For community, some locality or area is Society needs no area and the people essential."}{"question": "What is the definition of community?", "answer": "According to Bogardus, community is \u201ca social group with some degree of feeling and living in a given area\u201d."}{"question": "What are the elements of community?", "answer": "Elements of community Followings are the elements of community: 1."}{"question": "What are the end objectives of community?", "answer": "Ends and objectives of community are wider and natural not artificial."}{"question": "What does community mean?", "answer": "It means a feeling of belonging together."}{"question": "What is the difference between community and crowd?", "answer": "Unlike crowd, community is of permanent nature."}{"question": "What is the difference between population and society?", "answer": "Population is very essential for the Population is essential but more important formation of a community."}{"question": "What is the impact of computer on society?", "answer": "Impacts of computer on society: \u2022 Social Applications: Solve human/social problem such as \u2022 Medical Diagnosis \u2022 Computer assisted instruction \u2022 Government program planning \u2022 Environmental quality control \u2022 Law enforcement \u2022 Employment and productivity \u2022 Increase in employment & productivity \u2022 Reduction in specific type of job \u2022 Competition \u2022 Allows large organization to become more efficient or gain strategic competitive advantage?"}{"question": "What is the definition of computer virus?", "answer": "Small firms are driven \u2022 Individuality \u2022 Reduce human relationship \u2022 Inflexible \u2022 Quality of life \u2022 Production of better quality of goods/services at low costs/effort/time \u2022 Increase in leisure time \u2022 Eliminated monotonous tasks \u2022 Privacy \u2022 Collect, store, integrate, interchange and retrieve - easy \u2022 Lost privacy \u2022 Computer crime \u2022 Unauthorized use, access, modification and destruction of hardware /software /data \u2022 Unauthorized release of information, copying of software \u2022 Denying an end user access to his or her own hardware, software or data resources \u2022 Using or conspiring to use computer resource to commit felony (major crime) \u2022 Illegally obtain information or tangible property \u2022 Establish control for the purpose of unauthorized experimentation with computer resources \u2022 Computer viruses: It is a computer program that is potentially dangerous."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the word \"computer\"?", "answer": "6."}{"question": "What is the definition of computer viruses?", "answer": "They are not created or spontaneously generated but are designed for a specific malignant purpose."}{"question": "What is the definition of computer crime?", "answer": "Examples of computer crime: \u2022 Money Theft: Bank fraud \u2022 Computer viruses \u2022 Service Theft \u2022 Program and Data Theft \u2022 Program Copying \u2022 Data Alteration \u2022 Program Damage \u2022 Data Destruction \u2022 Malicious Access \u2022 Violation of Privacy \u2022 Violations of Antitrust or International Law Development and underdevelopment \u2022 One of the most significant of all social changes is the transition from pre-industrial to an industrial type of society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of computer viruses?", "answer": "community."}{"question": "What are the three categories of computer society?", "answer": "Based on the socioeconomic development of the society, the societies of the world have been grouped into three categories as first world, second world, and the third world."}{"question": "What is the meaning of computer viruses?", "answer": "Members are supposed to obey the Chances of personal development are commands and thus they have less much more as compared with the chances of personal development."}{"question": "What is the definition of computer viruses?", "answer": "They are not biological in nature but behave in similar manner."}{"question": "What countries are grouped as first world?", "answer": "\u2022 First world: Countries such as North America, Western Europe, Australia, Japan, Singapore etc."}{"question": "What is the history of engineering practice in eastern society?", "answer": "3 History of Engineering Practice in Eastern Society - summary \u2022 Civilization Developed (During 5000 BC."}{"question": "What are the countries that are grouped as third world?", "answer": "are grouped as third world."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of developing countries?", "answer": "They are less industrialized and developed."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of developing countries?", "answer": "They are less industrialized and underdeveloped."}{"question": "What are the countries that are grouped as first world?", "answer": "are grouped as first world."}{"question": "What is the main difference between the first world and the second world?", "answer": "Characteristic of developing countries: \u2022 Poverty/ unemployment/ under employment \u2022 Limited access to education and healthcare \u2022 Poor level of nutrition & health \u2022 Immature and unbalanced economy \u2022 Unstable political climate \u2022 Belief in culture \u2022 Lack of scientific /technological infrastructures \u2022 Less respect for time/ corruption Characteristic of developing countries (Western): \u2022 Achievement & success \u2022 Activity & work \u2022 Moral orientation \u2022 Efficiency & practicability \u2022 Progress \u2022 Material comfort \u2022 Equality \u2022 Freedom \u2022 Use of technology \u2022 Individualistic \u2022 High concern over time Technological achievement of 20th century: \u2022 High performance material \u2022 Nuclear Tech \u2022 Laser & optical fiber \u2022 Petrol & Gas Tech \u2022 Health technology \u2022 Household appliances \u2022 Imaging technology \u2022 Internet \u2022 Space exploration \u2022 Interstate highway \u2022 A/c Refrigeration \u2022 Telephone \u2022 Computer \u2022 Agriculture mechanization \u2022 Radio television \u2022 Electronic appliances \u2022 Safe & abundant water \u2022 Aero plane \u2022 Automobile \u2022 Electrification 1."}{"question": "What are the countries that are grouped as second world?", "answer": "are grouped as second world."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of developing countries?", "answer": "These countries are industrialized, stable and developed."}{"question": "What countries are grouped as third world?", "answer": "\u2022 Third world: Countries like Nepal, Bangaladesh etc."}{"question": "What countries are grouped as second world?", "answer": "\u2022 Second world: Countries such as Eastern Europe, Malasia etc."}{"question": "What is the meaning of engineering practice in western society?", "answer": "1."}